<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-23T23:28:46+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Analysis and Modelling Lab General Computational Skills</title><subtitle>Learning to love all things code; developing my skills in methods of analysis and modelling over a four-week period - or - 10 years of data and analysis developments in 20days!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">General Computational Skills</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/28/Gen-Comp-Skills.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="General Computational Skills" /><published>2019-01-28T17:39:07+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-28T17:39:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/28/Gen-Comp-Skills</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/28/Gen-Comp-Skills.html">&lt;p&gt;The topic takes the approach of learn through practice.  The topic begins with data storage; from rock carvings to databases, looking at appropriate application for each method as complexity requirements of the data increases. Data analysis is applied using the SQLite package and the preparation of data &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jfoth/AML/blob/master/JFotheringham_Comp_Skills_Day4/JFotheringham_CompSkills_Day4_sql.md&quot;&gt;(cleaning)&lt;/a&gt; prior to this is also explored, while guidence to best practice data collation is addressed throughout the course. This website is the culmination of the course, learning to use Jekyll to support my HTML webpage produced some challenges and random errors, which have been negated (possibly at the expense of a hardrive filled with missplaced Gem files…).
This excersice allows practice with Terminal command line control, markdown, Stackedit, SQLite and Github repositories.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The topic takes the approach of learn through practice. The topic begins with data storage; from rock carvings to databases, looking at appropriate application for each method as complexity requirements of the data increases. Data analysis is applied using the SQLite package and the preparation of data (cleaning) prior to this is also explored, while guidence to best practice data collation is addressed throughout the course. This website is the culmination of the course, learning to use Jekyll to support my HTML webpage produced some challenges and random errors, which have been negated (possibly at the expense of a hardrive filled with missplaced Gem files…). This excersice allows practice with Terminal command line control, markdown, Stackedit, SQLite and Github repositories.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Landuse Modelling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/21/Landuse-Change-Modelling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Landuse Modelling" /><published>2019-01-21T17:39:07+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-21T17:39:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/21/Landuse-Change-Modelling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/21/Landuse-Change-Modelling.html">&lt;p&gt;Using the GIS modelling progam ArcGIS and the ArcMap tool with R, this component introduced the concepts of optimal land-use, within the theme of governence and societal requirements and considering future climates (amongst other paratmeters).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the analysis was performed using the DynaClue model, which combines spatially explicit simulations of land-use change at a regional level based on suitability analysis, considering competition and interaction of possible elements on a space and time basis.  Practice in implementing and exploring the intrepretation of outputs was particularly satisfying given the visual nature of the discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Move to week 4 of the course: &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/28/Gen-Comp-Skills.html&quot;&gt;General Computational Skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Using the GIS modelling progam ArcGIS and the ArcMap tool with R, this component introduced the concepts of optimal land-use, within the theme of governence and societal requirements and considering future climates (amongst other paratmeters).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic Statistics in R</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/14/Basic-Stats.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic Statistics in R" /><published>2019-01-14T17:39:07+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-14T17:39:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/14/Basic-Stats</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/14/Basic-Stats.html">&lt;p&gt;This Course took the student through the concepts of basic statistics, including the reasoning behind methods used. The result was a working understanding of the base methods of statistical analysis and interpretation of the outputs of any treatments in the R progamming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course work followed the learning in Open Statistics, Third Edition [(PDF available for download)] (https://leanpub.com/openintro-statistics) and covered probability, inferencs, multiple regression and touched on linear regression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Move to week 3 of the course: &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/21/Landuse-Change-Modelling.html&quot;&gt;Landuse Change and Modelling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This Course took the student through the concepts of basic statistics, including the reasoning behind methods used. The result was a working understanding of the base methods of statistical analysis and interpretation of the outputs of any treatments in the R progamming language.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic Programming in Matlab</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/07/Matlab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic Programming in Matlab" /><published>2019-01-07T17:39:07+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T17:39:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/07/Matlab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/07/Matlab.html">&lt;p&gt;The first week of AML introduced the topic of Programming in MatLab, a condensed crash-course in programming in the language of Matlab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course moves through the functions of commands and basic language, before moving into utilisation and application over the remainder of the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working arrays, creating plots, graphic models and statistical applications are explored, and &lt;em&gt;flows&lt;/em&gt;: for and while loops are introduced where the iterative and conditional power of data analysis with machine learning is seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Move to week 2 of the course: &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/julia_aml/update/2019/01/14/Basic-Stats.html&quot;&gt;Statistics in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first week of AML introduced the topic of Programming in MatLab, a condensed crash-course in programming in the language of Matlab.</summary></entry></feed>